二零二五年安徽省初中学业水平考试。
一短对话理解。
你将听到五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，请在每小题所给的
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项。
每段对话读两遍。
What's your hobby, Simon?
I like reading and painting.
How about you, Sandy?
I enjoy running.
What's your hobby, Simon?
I like reading and painting.
How about you, Sandy?
I enjoy running.
2. We are finally at the top of the tower.
Look there! A small boat is passing through that ancient bridge.
We are finally at the top of the tower.
3. Tim, it's great that you and your sister are always trying something new.
Thanks, Aunt Mary.
My mom encourages us to do so.
Tim, it's great that you and your sister are always trying something new.
Thanks, Aunt Mary.
My mom encourages us to do so.
4. My doctor advised me to lose some weight.
I'm planning to do some exercise.
And don't eat too much fast food.
Eat more vegetables.
My doctor advised me to lose some weight.
I'm planning to do some exercise.
And don't eat too much fast food.
Eat more vegetables.
5. What instrument is this,
It's Erhu, a traditional Chinese musical instrument,
诶，
二。
长对话理解。
你将听到两段对话，每段对话。
话后有几个小题，请在每小题所给的
B, and questions.
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项。
每段对话读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答第六、七题。
That I will get on the bus at half past five, and get home at about six o
That's a little late.
Do you have anything special to do tonight?
I'll watch a ping -pong game first.
Then do some reading after dinner as usual.
Oh no, we just missed the bus.
Take it easy, John.
There will be another one in 15 minutes.
That means, I will get on the bus at half past five, and get home at about six o
That's a little late.
Do you have anything special to do tonight?
I'll watch a ping -pong game first.
Then do some reading after dinner as usual.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至十题。
What are you looking at?
Some club notices.
swimming club on Monday, the science club.
Hey Mike, why don't we join one together?
Sounds nice. How about the tennis club on Wednesday?
I'm not interested in tennis.
I like singing.
Let's go to the music club on Friday.
But Tom and I have chosen the drawing club on Friday.
Really? I like drawing too.
We can draw together in the club then.
Okay. Hello, Lucy.
What are you looking at?
Some club notices.
The swimming club on Monday, the science club.
Hey Mike, why don't we join one together?
Sounds nice. How about the tennis club on Wednesday?
I'm not interested in tennis.
I like singing.
Let's go to the music club on Friday.
But Tom and I have chosen the drawing club on Friday.
Really? I like drawing too.
We can draw together in the club then.
Okay. the A, B, and
三。
短文理解。
你将听到一篇短文，短文后有五个小题，请根据短文内容，在每小题所给
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项。
短文读两遍。
Today is the cleaning day.
It is a tradition in my family.
After I got up in the morning, I started to tidy up my bedroom.
Mom cleaned the kitchen and Dad cleaned the yard.
First, I went through all my clothes and decided to give some to my 11 -year -old
cousin. Then I put away my books.
Some of them were found behind my desk.
I also found a box of building blocks.
They were given by Grandma on my 10th birthday.
Under my bed, I saw my lost model plane.
It's my favorite toy.
When all was done, it was 12 o but I didn't feel tired.
I shouted to my parents to come in.
They were surprised to see the nice clean room and gave me a big hand.
I was very happy.
Today is the cleaning day.
It is a tradition in my family.
After I got up in the morning, I started to tidy up my bedroom.
Mom cleaned the kitchen and Dad cleaned the yard.
First, I went through all my clothes and decided to give some to my 11 -year -old
cousin. Then I put away my books.
Some of them were found behind my desk.
I also found a box of building blocks.
They were given by Grandma on my 10th birthday.
Under my bed, I saw my lost model plane.
It's my favorite toy.
When all was done, it was 12 o but I didn't feel tired.
I shouted to my parents to come in.
They were surprised to see the nice clean room and gave me a big hand.
I was very happy.
四、信息转换。
of word. Read the 5.
你将听到一篇短文，请根据短文内容写出下面表格中所缺的单词，每空仅
填一词。
短文读两遍。
Knowing how to start a is a great life skill.
If you're unsure of what to talk about with someone, here is some advice to help you
break the silence.
First, smile to get started.
If you look friendly, people will want to talk to you.
So, say hello to people with a smile.
Second, use starters to get talking.
Say something sweet such as I like your coat, or your coat is very nice.
Ask simple questions like who is your hero?
Or what is your favorite food?
Also, you can offer help, saying do you need any help with that?
Third, listen carefully and nod.
Show that you are interested in what people are saying.
Keep the conversation going by asking another question about what they've told you.
4. Conversation Knowing how to start a conversation is a great life skill.
If you're unsure of what to talk about with someone, here is some advice to help you
break the silence.
First, smile to get started.
If you look friendly, people will want to talk to you.
So, say hello to people with a smile.
Second, use starters to get talking.
Say something sweet such as I like your coat, or your coat is very nice.
Ask simple questions like who is your hero?
Or what is your favorite food?
Also, you can offer help, saying do you need any help with that?
Third, listen carefully and nod.
Show that you are interested in what people are saying.
Keep the conversation going by asking another question about what they've told you.
5. for
听力测试到此结束。